现在 有请学生致辞代表
And now, please welcome your valedictorian,
艾丽克斯·邓菲
Alex Dunphy.
我爸妈哪去了
Where are my mom and dad?
拐角要出现的是
and in this corner,
班级名次第一
finishing first in her class,
毕业典礼学生致辞代表
delivering the commencement address,
体重有 你多重来着 宝贝
weighing in at -- what do you weigh, honey?
爸
Dad!
同龄女孩标准体重
A healthy amount for a girl her age.
这些都拍下了吗
are you getting all this, buddy?
一句不漏
Pure gold.
她是智力大王
She's the main brain,
舞会奇葩 艾丽克斯·邓菲
the cerebellum of the ball, Alex Dunphy!!
继续拍啊 等我最终变疯子时
Oh, keep rolling, The News will want this footage
《新闻》肯定想要这段录像
when I eventually snap.
我还以为桑杰·帕特尔是全班第一呢
I thought Sanjay Patel was first in the class.
本来是的 不过他缺了几周课
He was until he missed a few weeks
因为他被自己造的机器人袭击了
and the robot he was building attacked him.
这种事还真发生了 人类啊
It's happening, people.
聪明反被聪明误
Our hubris will be our undoing.
宝贝 你跟我
Sweetie, what do you say you and I
一起去美甲怎么样
go and get our nails done, huh?
不了 我要背演讲稿
It's okay. I want to work on my speech.
老爸也经历过
Been there.
高中时 我获选了西语俱乐部财务委员
I remember the speech that won me treasurer
竞选演讲仍记忆犹新
of my high-school spanish club.
[西语]"我的名字叫菲利
"Mi nombre es Felipe.
我来到这座学校..."
Yo voy a la escuela..."
菲利 有完没完
Felipe.
这事可了不起啦
It was kind of a grande deal.
对手是地道的波多黎各人
I was up against an actual puerto rican.
真不去了吗 宝贝
Honey, are you sure?
说不定美甲师还能做出校园色呢
Because I think they can do school colors.
-不用了 妈妈 -好吧
- I'm good, mom. - Okay.
家庭重要大事总会让克莱尔情绪激动
Family milestones always throw Claire for a loop.
她会极力忍耐
She holds it in,
然后在第二天 会来个情绪大爆发
and then the next day, she has a total meltdown,
我就得收拾这个烂摊子
and I have to pick up the pieces.
可问题是 明天
Problem is, tomorrow,
我要和好哥们一起去拉斯维加斯
I'm supposed to go to vegas with my buds,
我得让她在今天就爆发出来
So...I need her to melt down today.
不然的话 可就真的"赌城奇事赌城止"了
Otherwise, what happens in Vegas won't happen to me
因为我去不了
because I won't be there.
百感交集的一天 对吧
Emotional day, huh?
喜悦的一天
Happy day.
悲喜交加吧
Happy and sad.
"兄弟们 老婆突然崩溃
"Guys, I can't go to Vegas
我去不了维加斯了"
because my wife's freaking out!"
相信我 这样的电话绝对
Trust me, that is not a phone call you want to make
不能打给前大学啦啦队的兄弟们
to a bunch of ex-college male cheerleaders.
他们能编出一套顺口溜来嘲笑你
They will mock you with a hurtful, rhythmic taunt.
喂
Hello?
歌洛莉亚 是我
Gloria, it's me.
医生怎么说
Ay! How was the doctor?
你回家的时候 能顺便捎点面包吗
Can you pick up some bread on the way home, please?
我到家了 院门遥控器坏了
I'm home. My damn gate remote won't work.
你能不能按一下...
Could you press...
-喂 -...9呢
- Hello? - ...9?
-曼尼 没事的 -什么没事
- Manny, it's okay. - What's okay?
出了什么事
What's wrong?
-你从哪打来的 -我没打给你啊
- Where are you calling from? - I'm not calling from.
是杰打的电话
Jay is calling.
杰又怎么了
What's wrong with Jay?
我的按钮坏了
My clicker won't work.
老天爷啊
Oh, my god
你心脏停跳了
your heart's not working?!
那你怎么还能和我们讲电话
How could you tell us this over the phone?!
我心脏没事
My heart is fine.
谁帮帮忙按下9键 放我进去行吗
Would somebody please press 9 and let me in?
-好的 -收到
- Okay .-Got it.
你们同时接 按下键也没用
It won't work if you're both on the line.
-那我挂了 -那我挂了
- Okay. - Okay.
怎么每次都这样
Every damn time!
来 莉莉 该穿衣服
Okay, Lily, time to get dressed. Okay.
一晃眼艾丽克斯居然要上高中了
I can't believe Alex is gonna be in high school.
我真是老了
I feel so old!
不光你一个人这么觉得
Oh, well, you feel old.
我看着她出生的
I was there when she was born --
就在产房
in the delivery room.
要我以前不是同志的话 我就[硬不起来了]
If I wasn't gay before, I --
得了吧 那你在农场2分钟都呆不了
Oh, please, you wouldn't have lasted two minutes on a farm.
什么动物产崽我都见过
I've witnessed all kinds of birthing --
眼睛都不带眨一下的
never batted an eye.
我见过牛生犊 猪产崽
I've seen cattle, I've seen hogs,
羊下羔...
I've seen goats --
我还见过一只三条腿的...
I've even seen a three-legged --
老天啊
Oh, my god!
-我不是故意的 -你笑得出来 米奇尔
- I'm sorry. - Really, mitchell?
我刚才可能就这么撒手人寰了
I could have just died.
凯茨勒校长 教职工们 家长们
Principal Kaizler, faculty, parents,
亲爱的同学们 今天站...
fellow graduates, it's --
嗨 小明星
Hey, superstar.
你在背演讲稿呢
Oh, you're working on your speech.
对的
Yep.
需要帮忙吗
Well, do you need any help?
因为有时候
Because sometimes it's great
应该向你敬重的人请教
to bounce ideas off someone whose opinion you value.
我就不用了
I'm good.
好吧 没关系
Okay. That's cool.
我们给你做做头发吧
We could do your hair.
咱可以做个杂志里那种发型
We could do it like we saw in that magazine.
就是那个女明星...叫什么名字来着
Oh, what's that actress -- what's her name? --
一排大白牙的那个
With the -- you know, with the teeth?
妈妈 别说了行吗
Mom, mom, please.
-我正专心准备呢 -好吧
- I'm -- I'm trying to concentrate. - Okay.
行
Okay.
你半个小时后就准备走吧
Well, you be ready to go in a half-hour,
我们要和你爷爷拼车去
because we are going to carpool with your grandpa.
海莉开车送我
Haley's driving me.
我想提前到校
I want to get there early.
想法不错
That's a great idea.
到时学校见
Great. I will see you there...
小明星
Superstar.
喂 熊妈妈 还好吗
Hey, mama bear. You okay?
别叫我"熊妈妈" 我才不是呢
Not with "Mama bear" I'm not.
-不要哭 -我没哭
- Don't cry. - I'm not crying.
嘘 难受就别忍着
Shh! Don't be brave.
我会陪伴你身边
I'm here for you.
直到明天下午两点 我将乘机前往维加斯
Until 2 p.m. Tomorrow, when my flight leaves for vegas.
你去哪了 你买面包回来了吗
Where were you? Did you bring the bread?
我被那扇门拒之门外
I was stuck outside that gate
等了足足10分钟它才开
for 10 minutes before it opened.
那就是没买面包咯
So no bread?
我们得把那破门修好
We got to get that thing fixed. Ay!
你的眼睛怎么了
What happened to your eye?
你是指什么
What are you talking about?
眼皮下垂
It's droopy.
你说"下垂"是什么意思
What do you mean, "Droopy"?
我不喜欢你变这样 杰
Aah. I don't like the look of that, Jay.
等下 我帮你查一查
Here, let me check something.
把那东西放一边去 我去看了皮肤科医生
Put that thing away. I saw my dermatologist.
他帮我检查下痣什么的
He was checking for moles or something.
可能注射了点麻药吧
He probably got some numbing cream on it.
没事
It's fine!
没什么可担心的
Nothing to worry about.
我去打肉毒杆菌了
I got botox.
被一个笨蛋医生忽悠的
Stupid doctor talked me into it,
现在都走样了
And now it's drifting.
我很久没觉得自己这么蠢了
I haven't felt this dumb since
上一次是花了30美元买了个
I shelled out 30 bucks for that bracelet
据说能让我身体平衡性更好的手镯
that's supposed to give me better balance.
-试着把我的手臂压下去 -好的
- Try to push my arm down. - Okay.
来吧 你做不到 你做不到
Go ahead. You can't do it. You can't do it.
-好的 我是做不到 -亲爱的 我回来了
- Okay. All right. I can't -- - Honey, I'm home.
你老爸的车怎么停在咱们家呢
Hey, uh, why is your dad's car here?
"在过去的三年中 大部分的同学
"It's ironic that I stand up here
都视我为隐形人
representing my classmates when,
而讽刺的是
for the past three years,
如今我却站在这里作为学生代表
most of them have treated me like I'm invisible.
这是我自找的
It's my own fault.
因为我在乎的是好成绩
I was obsessed with good grades
而不是长相 人气 或是紧身牛仔裤"
instead of looks, popularity, and skinny jeans."
什么 这就是你的演讲台词么
What?! Is that your speech?!
滚出去
Get out of here!
你不能说这些
You cannot say that!
当然能 你想知道为什么吗
Yes, I can! And you want to know why?
因为这都是实话
'cause it's the truth.
没有谁想听到实话
No one wants to hear the truth.
这很简单 艾丽克斯
It's very simple, Alex.
做一个好的演讲
In order to give a good speech,
你只是随便串几首歌名就行了
all you have to do is take a song and say it,
像是《永远相信自己》
like... "Don't stop believin'"
或是《开始狂欢吧》
or "Get this party started."
这没有任何意义
That means nothing.
谁在乎
Who cares?
没谁想要动脑子
Nobody wants to think.
这可是毕业礼
It's a graduation,
庆祝你们不需再开动脑筋的典礼
a celebration of being done with thinking.
人们想要被挑战
People want to be challenged.
他们会因此而尊敬我
They're gonna respect me for it.
以后没人会想跟你说话
No one's ever gonna talk to you again.
那又怎样
So what?
莫罕达斯·甘地 为了自己的信仰
Mahatma Gandhi went on a hunger strike
而绝食
for what he believed in.
那是因为没人愿意和他一起在餐厅吃饭
That's 'cause no one would eat with him in the cafeteria!
-伙计们 -我们在这
- Hey, guys! - We're here.
快过来 喝点柠檬水 吃点饼干
Come on over. Have some lemonade and cookies.
杰 看起来是不太妙啊
Jay, that's not looking very good.
没事的
It's fine.
速答 谁是总统
Quick! Who's the president?
-奥巴马 -菲尔 拜托
- Obama! - Phil, please.
我在测试是不是中风呢
I'm trying to rule out a stroke.
这不是中风
It's not a stroke.
为什么大家总觉得我会中风呢
Why does everybody always assume I'm having a stroke?
-年龄 -饮食
- Age. - Diet.
你忘记给我买面包了
You forgot to bring my bread.
对不起我们迟到了
I'm sorry we're late.
没事的 不过我们五分钟后要出发
That's okay. We got to leave in about 5 minutes, though.
卢克 不要玩弄那个球
Luke, stop pushing that ball around!
你会掉进去的
You're gonna fall in.
没错 然后你舅舅米奇尔
Oh, yes, and then your uncle Mitchell
就会幸灾乐祸
will laugh at your expense!
我是说这是一种性格缺陷
I'm just saying it's a character flaw.
够了够了 做个快速调查
Okay, okay, quick poll here.
今早 小卡穿戴整齐
This morning, Cam, fully dressed...
还好是穿着衣服会发生的事情
Thank god it's one of those stories.
当他正严肃地思考时
...while in the middle of a very serious thought,
突然掉进了小孩泳池
fell into a ducky pool.
老天 你没事吧
Oh, my goodness. Are you all right?
我没事 谢谢
Yes, I am. Thank you.
这才是正常的反应 爱和关心
That is a normal reaction -- love and concern.
好的 故事还没说完
Okay, wait, wait, wait, wait.
泳池都发出爆裂声了
The pool popped.
可怜的小东西
Ay! Poor thing!
-尾骨受伤后果不不堪设想啊 -我知道
- There is nothing worse than a tailbone injury. - I know.
真的假的 不不不
Seriously? No, no, no, no.
你们都是装出来的
You're so full of it.
你们明明觉得这很搞笑
You know this is funny.
想象一下 他这身形
Picture this
掉进一个小池子哦
falling into a tiny pool.
他这一周都会在这儿呆着哦 伙计们
He'll be here all week, folks!
我是说真的 你别想跟我回家
Literally, because you're not coming home with me.
她来了 小可爱斯黛拉来了
There she is. There's my little Stella.
我的乖狗狗
That's my girl.
亲爱的
Hi, sweetie.
你太可爱了
You're so cute,
我想把你的小脸蛋吃掉
I just wan eat your face!
还记得当初你也这么抱着艾丽克斯
You remember when you used to hold alex like that,
说她可爱的让你想吃掉吗
and you wanted to eat her face?
没错
Yeah.
现在她就要步入高中了
Now she's off to high school. Mm.
时光飞逝 对吧
Time marches on, huh?
没错
Yep.
你知道什么才是最悲伤的吗
You know what's really sad?
什么
What?
《泰坦尼克号》的结局
The end of "Titanic."
卢克
Hey, Luke.
你意识到两年后
Do you realize, in two years,
咱们就要小学毕业了吗
you and I will be graduating?
现在不是说这个的时候
Not now.
我在用意念移动这个球
I think I'm moving the ball with my mind.
呃 估计我毕业没问题
Well, I'll be graduating.
伙计们 别在心里暗自庆幸自己
You guys, stop congratulating yourselves
能装得那么富有同情心
for being so compassionate.
如果你们当时在场
If you had been there,
你们会跟我一样笑翻天的
you would have laughed just as hard as I did.
他过来了
He's coming.
不要说话
Stop talking.
他今天已经够丢脸了
He's been embaassed enough today.
忍住 忍住 忍住 忍住
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
怪不得啊
Wow. Now it makes sense.
原来这是普里契特家的共性
It's a Pritchett thing.
残酷冷血的遗传基因
Cruelty's genetic.
顿时认清了你们家族面目
Suddenly it's all very clear.
小心 你可能会撞上去哦
Be careful. You might run into it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
小卡 不好意思
I'm sorry, Cam. I'm sorry.
天啊 老爸 你的脸
oh, my god, dad, your face!
什么 没事没事
What? Oh, that's nothing, nothing.
没事的 我就去看了下皮肤科
It's boring. I went to the dermatologist.
无聊瞎鼓捣了下 我没事
It's a boring story. I'm fine.
-不 我们带你去医院 -我没事
- No, no, no, we got to get you to a hospital. - I'm fine.
是的 我带你去 走
Yes, I'm taking you. Come.
歌洛莉亚 不 等等
Gloria, no, wait.
你们在这等 歌洛莉亚
Wait right here! Gloria?
歌洛莉亚
Gloria?!
Gloria?
歌洛莉亚 等等
Gloria, hold on.
我的脸变成这样是因为我注射了
The reason my face looks like this is because I had...
肉毒杆菌
Botox.
女人们用来去皱纹的那玩意儿
Like the ladies use for their wrinkles?
事实上 将近10%的顾客是男性
Well, actually, nearly 10% of their sales are men,
但那无关紧要
But that's not important.
我注射后有反应不良
I had a bad reaction.
可能碰到神经或什么了
Hit a nerve or something.
很快就会好了
It's gonna go away soon.
干嘛 你这是什么态度
What? What's that supposed to mean?
没什么
Nothing.
你可以不要这样吗
Would you stop?
我已经够难堪的了
This is very embarrassing for me.
我也是
For both of us.
他没事 虚惊一场
He's fine. It was a false alarm.
你说虚惊一场是什么意思
What do you mean, a false alarm?
他的脸白的跟蜡烛一样
His face looks like a candle.
她都说了 我没事
You heard her. I'm okay.
她又不是医生
She's not a doctor.
你也不是
Neither are you.
就差法律认证而已
Technically.
好吧 我不知道到底是怎么回事
Okay, look, I don't know what's going on her
但这样绝对是不正常的
But there is no way that this is normal.
你看起来就像是 肉毒杆菌注射失败
You look like a botox job gone horribly wrong.
上帝啊 你不会真是吧
No...my...God. You didn't.
他当然不是啦
Of course he didn't.
到底是不是
Did you?
不
No.
你就是
You did!
你到底在想什么 你可是个老兵啊
What were you thinking? You're a veteran.
够了 谈话到此为止 我们走
Enough! This conversation is ended. Let's go.
你们觉得他连屁股也整了吗
Do you think he got his butt done, too?
看起来相当正啊
It looks fantastic.
艾丽克斯 等下 对不起
Alex, wait. I'm sorry.
如果你想按那稿子讲 就这样做吧
If you want to give your speech, go ahead.
我从来没致过词 没资格说三道四
I was never valedictorian. What do I know?
谢谢
Thank you!
我这么做是有原因的
I am doing this for a reason.
我不是
It's not just like I'm --
对不起 艾丽克斯 以后你会谢我的
Aha! Sorry, Alex, but you will thank me one day!
拜托 你觉得我会没有副本吗
Please. You really think I don't have duplicates?
如果你这么做 你会变成社交圈的食人鱼[社交怪胎]
If you do this, you'll be a social piranha.
是的 我会成为亚马逊肉食性鱼类
Yes, I'll be an amazonian carnivorous fish.
肉食什么
Carniv-- what?!
爸爸 开门
Dad, open the gate.
完了 关键时刻掉链子
Oh, geez, not now!
怎么了 发生什么事了
What? What's happening?
门又卡住了
It's stuck again.
门卡住是什么意思
What do you mean, it's stuck?
你不能打开吗
Can't you get it open?
"卡住"不就是打不开的意思吗 克莱尔
What do you think "stuck" Means, Claire?
我们得想点办法 老爸
We have to do something, dad.
你能不能把门推开 或用别什么方法吗
Can't you -- can't you push it open or something?
不知道
I don't know!
我们困在你的车道上
We are trapped in your driveway,
你说不知道怎么办
and you don't know?
老爸 作为这扇门的主人
As a gate owner, dad,
你要负责
you have a certain responsibility.
我女儿将要
See, my daughter is gonna get up on that stage
登台演讲
and give a speech
然后从中学毕业
and graduate from middle school,
如果我不能在场的话 我会崩溃的
and if I am not there, dad, I am going to freak out!
我会崩溃的
I am going to freak out!
-或许可以推开 -你明白我的心情吗
- Maybe push it.- Do you understand what I am saying?
你明白这有多重要吗
Do you have any idea how important...
-你为什么在笑 -我没有 我没有笑
- Why are you smiling? - I'm not -- I'm not smiling.
歇斯底里的妻子
Hysterical wife.
中奖[模仿老虎机中奖]
Jackpot.
拜托
Come on.
好吧 我们试试这个方法
All right. Okay, we have tried this way.
把门撞开 孩子们 让开
I say we ram the gate. Kids, get out of the way.
等等 我觉得我可以搞定
Hold on! I think I can fix this!
我需要一个回形针 橄榄油
I just need a paper clip, some olive oil,
还要缎带
and a ribbon.
你准备怎么做 能工巧匠
What's the plan, "Macgayver"?
事实上 回形针
Actually, the paper clip
是用来连接这两个电路的
is to connect these two circuits,
橄榄油是用来润滑的
and the olive oil is to lubricate the mechanism.
缎带是给莉莉的
And the hair ribbon is for Lily.
她的发型让我抓狂了一天了
Her hair's been driving me crazy all day.
我们可以打车去
Why don't we just call some cabs?
因为 米奇尔 这里不是泰晤士广场
Because, Mitchell, this is not Times Square,
我们打不到车的
and they'll take forever.
那我们爬过围墙 跑步过去
Well, then we'll just climb over the fence and start running.
不 菲尔 学校离这5英里
No, we won't, because it's 5 miles away, Phil!
我还穿着美美的高跟鞋 所以不行
And I'm in big shoes, so, no.
等下 等下
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
救星来啦
I save the day.
骑这个笨脚踏车去吧
Let's take this crazy bicycle,
我们先把它扔到门外
we throw it over the gate,
然后把菲尔和克莱尔
Then we take Phil and we take Claire,
也一起扔到门外去
and then we throw them over the gate, too.
好吧 这是到底是什么玩意儿
All right, what the hell is that?
杰买的
Jay bought it.
他觉得我们会用到
He thought we were gonna use it all the time,
但是我骑的时候 膝盖一直碰到胸部
But I keep hitting my boobs with my knees.
甜蜜的负担 对不
Champagne problems, right?
亲爱的 他们不会骑这脚踏车的
Honey, they're not gonna ride the bike.
但我还是觉得我们应该把它扔过去
Yeah, but I still think that we should throw it over the gate.
好吧 你知道吗
Okay, you know what?
谢谢 谢谢了
Thank you. Thank you.
没人想出有建设性的办法
Nobody else has come up with an idea.
我有办法
I think I've got a good idea.
伙计 我们没时间造火箭
We don't have time to build a rocket, buddy.
那算了
Never mind.
好了
Okay. So...
那菲尔和我先过去
Phil and I will go over first,
然后你们把车扔过来
And then you guys will throw over the bike?
好了 上来吧 我把你举上去
Okay, step up. I'll boost you.
咱们不能找架梯子来吗
Couldn't we get a ladder?
拜托 我当拉拉队叠罗汉的时候
Please, on cheer squad I boosted girls bigger than you
还举过比你壮的女生呢
to the top of a human pyramid.
现在 手放两边
Now, arms at your side.
身体打直
Straight like a pencil.
一 二...
One, two...
我们壮如斗牛犬
We are bulldogs!
她没事
She's fine.
好了 杰 现在该你来弄我了
Okay. Jay, now you do me.
用力一把抓就行 别害羞
Just grab a handful. Don't be shy.
现在没剩多少肉了
I'm not giving you as much to work with.
以前挺丰满的 现在瘦了不少
I used to have a lot more there. I lost it.
他们以前都叫我"肥臀"
They used to call me "The grand can."
"讽刺的是 如今我却站在这里
"It's ironic that I stand up here
作为学生代表 在过去的三年中"
Representing my classmates when, for the past..."
我读完你的演讲稿了
I read the rest of your speech.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
你是讨厌我吗
Do you hate me?
什么
What?!
你说那些受欢迎的孩子们有多肤浅多不堪
You talk about how all the popular kids are shallow and lame.
我并不是在说你
I didn't mean you.
你以为你把每个人都看得很透彻
You think you have everyone figured out,
但是其实每个人都有自己的难言之隐
but everybody has their stuff.
你能有什么难言之隐
What "Stuff" do you have?
有太多男孩追 还是有太多派对要参加
Too many boys chasing after you? Too many parties?
你真的想知道我有什么难言之隐吗
You really want to know what "stuff" I have?
没错
Yeah.
我的生物课挂科了
I'm flunking out of biology.
现在我不得不去上暑期班
And now I have to go to summer school.
我的朋友们 他们现在讨论的唯一话题
My friends -- all they can ever talk about nowadays
就是上大学
is going off to college,
而我甚至都不确定自己是否能上大学
and I don't even know if I can get into college.
这点难言之隐对你来说够了吗
Is that enough "Stuff" For you?
随便吧
Whatever.
你知道吗
You know what?
随你好了 照着你那破稿子念吧
Fine. Give your stupid speech.
享受被人排挤的生活吧
Be an outcast.
但你这么做只会害到自己
But you're only doing it to yourself
因为你聪明又漂亮
because you're smart and pretty
还透着一股虽然我不太懂
and sort of funny in a way that I don't really get
但其他人似乎很喜欢的幽默感
but other people seem to enjoy,
所以 要么你明年开始新生活
So, you can either start fresh next year
要么成为那个对全班竖中指的怪胎
or be the freak who flipped off her class.
你真的我觉得我漂亮吗
You really think I'm pretty?
闭嘴
Shut up!
菲尔 走直线
Phil, go straight!
这样会更快
This way's faster!
不要 直着走
No, straight!
别再往那边歪了
Stop leaning!
-你想来开路吗 -我想
- Do you want to drive?! - I do.
没门 是我先说的
Tough, I called it!
我晕
D'oh.
那是怎么回事
What was that?!
妈的 车链子断了
Oh, crap. The chain broke!
接着蹬就行了 那个不要紧的
Just keep pedaling. It doesn't matter.
那个有点要紧
It matters a little!
小卡 务必要小心啊
Cam, please be careful.
为什么
Why?
要是我被电死了 我的帽子就会爆飞
If I get electrocuted, my hat might blow right off.
而这个场景很可笑 对吗
That would be funny. It's that, all right?
不是 不是
No, no.
杰
Hey, Jay!
我知道你觉得难为情
I know you're feeling self-conscious,
所以我找了点对你有用的东西
so I dug out something I thought might help.
把那玩意儿拿开
Put that thing away.
我就知道你会这么说 但听我说完
I knew you'd say that, but hear me out.
这是专门为惊悚恐怖的人
This was designed to make
变身超酷型男而设计的
A hideously disfigured man look supercool.
这简直太适合你了
It's perfect for you.
哎呀 太恶心了 好吧
Oh, yikes. Okay.
我上楼去看看 还有没有左边脸的
I'll go upstairs and see if I hava lefty.
别那么看着我
Don't look at me like that.
我不得不说 我对你去做这种事
I have to say that I am a little disappointed
感到有点失望
in you doing this thing.
我可不失望
Not me.
我感觉好极了
I feel real good about it.
我都告诉你多少遍了
Now many times do I have to tell you
不需要特地为我变年轻
that you don't have to look young for me?
我不是为了你才那么做的
I didn't do it for you.
那是为了谁
What is her name?!
别闹了
Stop.
大多数时候 我边走边想
Most of the time, I walk around,
在脑子里想 觉得自己只有四十岁
and in my head, I'm 40.
而当我照镜子的时候
Then I look in the mirror,
我会问自己 "这个老男人是谁
I say, "Who's that old man?
他在我的浴室做什么"
And what's he doing in my bathroom?"
那也是我的浴室啊
Well, it's my bathroom, too.
我喜欢那里面有个老男人
And I like when the old guy is there.
我爱上的就是你这张脸
This is the face that I fell in love with.
不是这边
Not this face --
是这半边
This one.
门打开了 门打开了
The gate's opening! The gate's opening!
-你怎么做到的 -我什么也没做
- How did you do that? - I didn't do anything.
是我做的
I did it.
我用我的思想打开了它
I opened it with my mind.
大家快来
Come on, guys!
-咱们快走吧 -对 咱们走
- Let's go, guys! - Yeah, let's go.
-曼尼 -快去叫曼尼
- Manny! - Get manny.
所有人都上车 咱们走
Everyone in the car. Let's go!
没错 跟我想的一样 链子断了
Yep. That's what I thought. Chain's broken.
你有什么想法
What do you think?
我觉得咱们得走了
I think we gotta go.
宝贝 我们 我们不可能走着去
Sweetie, we-- we can't make it on foot.
我们总得试试
We have to try.
宝贝
Honey.
Honey!
没事的
It's okay.
怎么会没事 菲尔
It's not okay, phil!
明明有事 我们就要失去她了
It's not okay. We're losing her.
-艾丽克斯吗 -对
- Alex? - Yes.
你不会失去她的
You're not losing her.
会的 她要去上高中了
We are. She's going to high school.
我当初也是这么失去海莉的
This is just when I lost Haley.
海莉从我印象中可爱小天使
This is when Haley went from being my sweet little angel
变成一个情绪化
to being a moody,
爱发短信 又蛮横无理的傲娇公主
texting, snotty little princess
而且她还讨厌我
who hates me.
海莉才不讨厌你
Haley doesn't hate you.
而且我们也不会失去她
And we're not losing her.
你还记得你以前下班回到家
Do you remember when you used to come home from work
海莉会穿着她的小"阿拉丁"睡衣
and Haley would meet you at the door
在门口迎接你吗
in her little "Aladdin" Pajamas?
而且 她还会高举着双臂
And, you know, she'd stick her arms up in the air
然后说 "老爸老爸 带我一起去魔毯之旅"
And say, "Daddy, daddy, take me on a magic carpet ride."
还记得吗
Remember that?
离上次海莉见到你很兴奋有多久了
When was the last time Haley was that excited to see you?
久到我忘了
I don't remember. It's been so long.
我们又要失去另一个女儿了
We're losing another one.
孩子们就是这样的 他们离开
And that's what kids do -- they leave.
一个接一个地离开 然后再也不回来
They leave, and they -- and they don't come back.
我们的孩子会回来的 对吧
Well, ours will come back, right?
要是不回来呢
What if they don't,and --
很快 就只剩我们俩了
and, pretty soon, it's just the two of us?
我再也不想去维加斯了
I don't want to go to Vegas anymore.
我知道
I know.
我只想抱着他们
I just want to hug them
让他们在朋友面前出糗
and embarrass them in front of their friends.
我知道
I know.
艾丽克斯 天啊
And Alex -- my god.
要是我们错过了演讲
If we miss this speech --
亲爱的 她是咱家老二
Honey, she's a middle child --
她不会原谅我们的
She will never forgive us.
我们不会错过演讲的
We're not missing that speech!
停车 停车
Hello! Hello!
你要怎么做 菲尔
What's the plan, Phil?
我叫菲利
Mi nombre es Felipe.
你开去...
Yo voy...
一个学校
a la escuela.
你想搭顺风车去学校
You need a ride to the school.
是的 拜托了
Yes, please!
你叫菲利
Felipe?
行了
Okay.
快点 兄弟
V anos,muchachos!
我很荣幸站在
I am so proud to be standing
这一群杰出的青少年面前
in front of this extraordinary group of youngsters.
抱歉 或者我应该改成"老生们"
I'm sorry -- or should I say "Oldsters"?
但说实话 "毕业典礼"这词
But seriously, the word "Commencement"
代表的是"开始"
means "Beginning."
我很抱歉我笑话了你
I'm sorry I laughed.
我才不要你道歉
I don't need an apology,
但必须要说你今天的行为
But I will say your behavior today
让人大开眼界
has been very eye-opening.
无意冒犯 杰
No offense, Ja
没事 你看上去像个冰山
None taken. You look like an iceberg.
行了
Okay.
是这儿 就这儿
This is...right here.
好了 快走
Okay. Let's go.
非常感谢 兄弟
Muchas gracias, muchachos!
太客气了
You're quite welcome!
现在 我们有请学生致辞代表
And now, please welcome your valedictorian,
艾丽克斯·邓菲
Alex Dunphy.
我爸妈呢
Where's my mom and dad?
谢谢
Thank you.
他们来了
Mm -- there they are!
快点 菲尔
Come on, Phil!
敬爱的凯斯勒校长
Principal Kaizler...
-等等 菲尔 -全体老师
- Hold on, Phil! ... - faculty...
-亲爱的 我滑倒了 -天呐 菲尔
- Oh, sweet cream! I'm sliding! - Oh, my god, phil!
-校董成员 -我抓住你了 起来
...school-board administrators... - I got you. Get up. Get up.
-我抓住你了 -各位毕业生
- I got you. ... - fellow graduates...
对不起对不起
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!
各位家长 以及
...parents, and everyone
伴我们度过具有挑战的青春期阶段的每一位
who helped us through these challenging formative years,
小卡 你这是五十步笑一百步
Cam! You have lost all credibility.
-这可不一样 -怎么不一样
- This is completely different. - How?
这是荒诞的喜剧和
It's the juxtaposition of absurdist comedy
对战正式场合的背景
against the backdrop of a formal setting...
而不是一个大男人跌进了游泳池
Not a big-boned man falling into a pool.
-是嘛 -别说话 艾丽克斯才是焦点
- Really? - Shh! This is about alex.
我在此代表我的同学发言真是有点讽刺
It's ironic that I stand up here representing my classmates
那个...
when...
他们都很
...they're so...
出色
awesome...
他们都应该自己站在这里
They should be up here themselves.
但我站这里了
But I'm up here, and...
我要说的是
I'm sayin'...
难言之隐
stuff,
因为每一个人都有自己的
'cause everybody's got their...
难言之隐
stuff,
不论你是人气王
whether you're popular
或是滑稽怪人
or a drama geek...
或是啦啦队队长
or a cheerleader...
或者像我这样的书呆子
or even a nerd like me.
我们都有自己的不足
We all have our insecurities.
是的 都有
Yes, we do.
我们都在努力证明自己
We're all just trying to figure out who we are.
我要说的是
I guess what I'm trying to say is...
永远 相信 自己
...Don't stop...believin'...
开始狂欢吧
...Get this party started.
太棒了
That's so cute.
不是吧
Seriously?
她过来了
There she is.
美女
That girl.
你的演讲让我很感动
Your speech moved me.
我太爱你这么引用歌的名字
I loved how you play with the song titles.
太厉害了
Fantastic.
我想的哦
My idea.
孩子 做得不错
You did good, kid.
谢谢祖父
Thanks, grandpa. Aah!
别问为什么 他会好的
Don't ask. He'll be fine.
是的 我们都以你为豪
Yes. We are so proud of you.
亲下
Come here.
你好
Hello.
我用意念打开心门
I opened a gate with my mind.
我们去吃点东西好吗
What do you say we all go get something to eat?
我们去吧
Let's do it. Yeah.
其实 我被邀请去一个派对
A-actually, I was kind of just invited to a party.
我能过去吗
Would it be okay if I go?
当然可以
Yeah. Of course.
-可以啊 -太好了
- Yeah. - Yay!
孩子 去吧
See you, kid. Have fun.
玩的高兴点 谢谢你们能来
Thanks for coming, you guys!
再见再见
Bye! Bye! Bye! Bye!
恭喜啊
Congratulations!
老妈我饿了
I'm kind of hungry, mom.
天啊 她回来了
Oh, my god. She's back.
-我的宝贝 -什么
- My baby. - What?
-我的宝贝 -我的天啊
- My baby. - Oh, my god.
-我的小宝贝 -你们做什么啊
- My little baby. - What are you doing?
我们走 去吃东西
Let's go. Let's go eat.
-我已经饱了 -不吃会后悔的哦
- I'm not hungry amore. - Oh, you're not gonna regret this.
我要吃点虾
I could use some shrimp.
我不 我不饿了
I'm not hu-- I'm not hungry.
我真不饿了
I'm not hungry anymore.
你饿了 你肯定饿了
Sure you are. Sure you are.
不 我真不饿了
I'm not -- no, I'm not.